All right. So University of South Carolina women's basketball coach Dawn Staley said that transgender women and girls should be allowed to compete on female sports teams, giving a lift to transgender rights ahead of her team's NCAA championship victory. Let's take a listen.
Do you think transgender women should be able to participate? That's the question you want me to ask. I mean, you want to ask. I'll give you that. Yes. Yes. So now the barnstorm of people are going to flood my timeline and be a distraction to me on one of the biggest days of our game. And I'm OK with that. I really am.
So here's the thing. I know that people have very, very, very, very, very strong feelings about this. But the truth is we as a society have to expand. And the first step to expansion is considering something different than what we're accustomed to. And that's very, very difficult for us as a society, like particularly just in America. Like it's very like, oh, this is how it is. I mean, there's literally a whole movement of, quote unquote, make America great again.
And what they're basically saying is like, let's go back to slavery. We never liked that it changed.
In order to expand, you have to make more room. When we look at this conversation, this is not an exact replication, but it's something that I just want to bring to your attention in a similar way.
The reason why we are seeing the reversal of DEI, the reason why we're seeing the, you know, onslaught against African-American studies, the reason why we're seeing so much police brutality is because America never expanded for black people.
It just included, but it didn't expand. And the inclusion is literally like, I will let you just you in because there's no there's not that we're already filling up space and we're not going to we're not going to take it.
We're not going to get any of our spaces up just to bring you in. So the only way to do that is to expand.
And, you know, in many ways that was able to happen by just black people creating our own spaces. Right.
And being like, all right, well, if you're not going to let us in your space, we'll come in your own space and our own space.
And I would never, ever, ever tell a community that I'm not a part of what to do.
But I think that there is something to be said for spaces being created by the people who really are at the helm of their own peace.
And the frustrating part is that you're like, yeah, but I deserve what I deserve.
And it's like, that's the whole terrible part about this place is that you can deserve, but that doesn't mean they're going to give it.
This country ain't never giving nobody what they deserve ever.
They just fold once you demand enough or when you take up enough space.
And so what Dawn Staley is saying, I think, is very encouraging to the trans community as someone who's not a member of it,
but who I can imagine because she is a champion.
She's on the biggest sports stage of college sports right now.
And ultimately, it is a real conversation topic.
I know people were like, why would he ask her that question?
Blase, boom.
But these are real questions and people are really talking about them.
And I think it is just really a testament to her class and just to who she is that she's like, this is how I feel.
I know y'all are going to come for me.
It's fine.
It's also just so crazy because people act like there's going to be like a flood of trans people coming to play.
And I'm like, what are y'all talking about?
There's barely even a flood of women's basketball players as it is.
So cut it out.
Just expand.
We all would do better to expand.
I'm telling you, I promise you, like when we make more room, it doesn't mean that you are now constricted.
It means that you have even more room to breathe and you have more people to share with.
And I think that's the beauty of community.
We are, we are, we are.